A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom, Media, Arts, and Culture, Media Unit, Office Files of Becky Lentz FA1426
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conference Materials and Publications, 2000-2007; 2
  - Institute of International Education Travel Grants, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 122)
    Electronic Media Policy Portfolio: A Summary Report of IIE Travel Grants Fiscal Year 2005; A Report on the Second AfroGEEKS Conference May 2005, Prepared by Dr. Mary Bertran; memos and correspondence; Report on Cultural Studies Association Conference April 2005, Prepared by Dr. Mary Beltran; Developing Metrics for Measuring Viewpoint Diversity in Local Media Markets, Mark Lloyd amd Philip Napoli; The Public Airwaves as a Common Asset and a Public Good: Implications for the Future of Broadcasting and Community Development in the US; The Role of Grassroots Organizing in Challenging Media Consolidation in the US; Reports on the National Conference on Media Reform, May 2005
  - International Funders for Indigenous Peoples, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 123)
    Pamphlets; International Funders for Indigenous Peoples 5th Annual Conference May 16 and 17, 2006; Newsletters 2003-2005
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program - All Staff Reflections, 2006 October (Box 19, Folder 124)
    OVP, ESR, MAC, ESR/MAC, GAs, AAs
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program - New York Staff Retreat, El Museo del Barrio, Teatro Heckscher, New York City, 2006 September 19 (Box 19, Folder 125)
    Agenda, OVP Reflections, ESR Reflections, MAC Reflections, GAs' Reflections, AAs' Reflections, Conference Information
  - Report on the 2nd Learning Workshop on Representing Class, Ethnicity, Gender, and Race to the Public, Irma McClaurin, 2007 February 1-2 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Low Power Radio (LPFM), 2001 (Box 19, Folder 127)
    Correspondence; 2001 meeting documents
  - Media, Arts, and Culture Global Meeting, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    Proposed Action and Learning Steps, Points of Agreement, Points of Difference, Storytelling Discussion Groupings, Charge to Small Groups
  - Media, Arts, and Culture Learning Circle Meeting (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 19, Folder 129)
    Correspondence and memos; Ghana Trip travel information; Agenda and Schedule; Regional Programming in Africa and the Middle East; Global Exchange of Ideas: The African Marketplace, Mercado Cultural, Africa in Venice, The World Culture Forum Alliance
  - Media, Arts, and Culture Learning Circle Meeting (2 of 2), 2006 (Box 19, Folder 130)
    10th Year Anniversary 1996 to 2006, New York and Washington, DC - Briefing Book
  - Media, Arts, and Culture Learning Group, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 131)
    Convening of the Media, Arts, and Culture Learning Group, 24-26 October 2002, Oakland, California
  - Media Grants - Miscellaneous, 2005-2006 (Box 20, Folder 132)
    Ford Foundation - Global Perspectives in a Digital Age
  - Media Justice Organizations and Publications (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 133)
    The Bay Area Media Map: A Youth Organizer's Guide to the Media Turf in the Bay Area and Beyond, Youth Media Council; A Public Forum on Media Ownership in Philadelphia (May 2003); Common Cause info sheets; Youth Media Council: Transforming Media Communicating Justice Publications; Looking Deeper: A Report on the Visibility and Invisibility of Youth, Policy and Race in the San Jose Mercury News, Youth Media Council (May 2005); Is KMEL the People's Station?: A Community Assessment of 106.1 KMEL (Fall 2002)
  - Media Justice Organizations and Publications (2 of 2), 2006 (Box 20, Folder 134)
    Why Media Matters pamphlets for labor activists, for independent artists, for community organizers, for parents and families, for faith groups, for immigrant groups, for environmental advocates; Speaking for Ourselves: A Youth Assessment of Local News Coverage; Investing in Youth Media: A Guide for Grantmakers; Media Activist Toolkit; 40 Years of Impact: Film and Video Festival Catalog, Council on Foundations
  - Youth Made Media, Open Society Institute, Youth Initiatives, Youth Media Program - DVD, DVD, Total running time: 17:30 (Box 20, Folder 134)
  - Media Reform, Media Justice, and Media Democracy, undated (Box 20, Folder 135)
  - Native American Grantmaking, 2001-2007 (Box 20, Folder 136)
    List of Native American Issues Grants from the Media, Arts, and Culture Division; Recommendations to the Ford Foundation to Enhance and Strengthen Native American Grantmaking; Ford Foundation Electronic Media Policy: Report on the Native American Convening and Participation in the National Conference for Media Reform (January 11-14, 2007)
  - Privacy Organizations and Publications, 2000-2004 (Box 20, Folder 137)
    Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) publications and annual reports; Exhibit: Observing Surveillance; Business Week - Online Privacy: It's Time for Rules in Wonderland; The Atlantic Monthly Special Report - Homeland Insecurity; National Journal Special Report - Privacy's Price
  - Reflection Memo, Becky Lentz, 2004 September (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Women's International News Gathering Service I-VI, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 139)
    Report: Suggested Ideas for Ford Foundation Funding Related to Media Technology and Regulation (July 6, 2002); Progress or No Room at the Top?: The Role of Women in Telecommunications, Broadcast, Cable and E-Companies (March 14, 2001); FEM-ACCESS Program - Women in Community Radio: An Assessment of their situation and the elaboration of an adapted training methodology: Funding Proposal; press articles
  - Women's International News Gathering Service VII-XIV, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 140)
    Press materials; Draft Text for the FCC's Strategic Plan, 2003-2008
  - Women's International News Gathering Service XV-XXII, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 141)
  - Women's International News Gathering Service XXII-XXXII, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 142)
  - Remaking the Media: Public Interest Agendas and Strategies/Groups Working to Change the Media System: Agendas and Strategies - 2 posters, undated (Box 21, Folder 143)